Guide to the Stanford University, Art Department, Files Regarding Albers Wall
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stanford University, Art Department, files regarding Albers Wall
1973-1980
SC0301
Stanford University. Art Department.
0.75 Linear feet
Correspondence, architectural plans and other materials regarding the controversial acquisition and placement of Albers Wall (outdoor art) at Stanford University, dedicated August 1, 1980. Correspondents include Prof. Albert Elsen, Assoc. Provost Edward E. Shaw, and architects Craig Ellwood and Robert Mittelstadt.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Information about Access
This collection is open for research.
Associated Materials
Additional architectural drawings for this project are housed within the Stanford University Archives Architectural Drawings Collection.
Description of the Collection
Correspondence, architectural plans and other materials regarding the controversial acquisition and placement of Albers Wall (outdoor art) at Stanford University, dedicated August 1, 1980. Correspondents include Prof. Albert Elsen, Assoc. Provost Edward E. Shaw, and architects Craig Ellwood and Robert Mittelstadt.
Access Terms
Albers, Josef; Ellwood, Craig.; Elsen, Albert Edward, 1927-; Mittelstadt, Robert.; Shaw, Edward E.; Stanford University. Art Department.; Stanford University. Department of Art.; Albers Wall.
Collection Contents
- Files
  - Correspondence, 1971-72 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, Jan.-June 1977 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Law School poll, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Communications with donors (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence concerning opposition, 1975-76 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Miscellaneous materials (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Clippings (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Dedication materials and construction documents, 1977-80 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 4)